yesterday I held the preliminary event
or a new idea which was we nicknamed
oxytocin 36 people get together in pairs
and answer the 36 questions that are in
the description of the YouTube video
that I'm currently doing and it was it
wasn't a success
FaceTime no unzoom we did it on Zoom so
one of my friends borrowed a paid zoom
account she was a co-host and then I put
it out and four people signed up only
one person one of my friends showed up
so Carrie ended up watching well my
friends and I did the 36 questions which
is why it both was a success and wasn't
a success one person showed up which
theoretically in the past might have not
felt like a success but the fact I had a
co-host this time felt less vulnerable
and more safe and then the person who
showed up I really loved and it was
great to sit and have a hour and a half
conversation with him then also when
putting this together to update you all
I had been linking to the New York Times
36 questions and people were like it's
behind a paywall it hasn't been hunted
behind a paywall for me but so I linked
to a different one and it's the same
questions but they have a different
procedure because there's three sets of
questions 12 12 and 12 and I mean Daniel
magic turns answering them both and it
takes a lot it takes like an hour and a
half to go through them all but this
article that's linked suggest actually
spending 15 minutes on the first set and
when you're done the 50 the wind 15
minutes expires you go on to the second
set and it's been 15 minutes than 15
minutes and that actually works because
we wanted to keep it to an hour for the
zoom conversations however only one
person showed up part of that was my
branding I was like followed by with a
fellow human being which is too big it
needs to be like and I do want to say
develop a deep connection but even
that's probably too big it's like come
experience affection for your fellow
human is that is that too big I don't
know but
and also so the possibility of a future
one I would like to do with a group of
people as opposed to me putting it on
and hoping a group of people show up or
I just keep posting them and hope that
people show up which doesn't feel like
this isn't the kind of thing that the
same person can show up to again and
again that's not true so like if just
Daniel showed up and it's time we were
paired off it doesn't work but if the
three of us show up I guess you know
Kerry and Daniel can have a have a
conversation but if it can grow
naturally if people can bring friends
because they enjoy the experience then
there's always gonna be more people to
to meet what to pair off with the idea
was eventually it would be its own
platform but if people don't see the
beauty of it if they're too scared for
whatever reason or two turned off
whatever I'm offering in that moment
then they're not going to come and
experience it to decide for themselves
is this something of value and so I can
only offer so much to the world of value
if they're not taking it right and I can
only offer it in the way I'm currently
offering it I can't do much else
luckily Kerry and I have found one
another and she does fill a lot of the
roles that I I can't bill I'm also
starting a whole new fire with community
started because I no longer want to live
in the city I want to live out where I
can have a dog and a cat mother my kid
can have a dog in a cat or there's other
kids where there's nature but I have
none of the financial capacity to do
that um usually costs a lot of money I
can't buy the land that you don't even
have enough money for a tiny house even
if I was making it myself
but I do know the power of groups coming
together I was involved in the cohousing
community that I'm involved with in
Vancouver since the beginning I just
couldn't afford to buy and/or rent there
so I know what the process is of
starting a community and what I've tried
to put forward restarting like a Medic a
meta community conversation not hey
let's start a new new community I know
how difficult that is
it's like find the lands people fall off
because it's the rot like and I'm
working with a global community Soho
trying to figure out what is the meta
conversation for that what do you need
to start a community and one of the
people and there's actually written a
book on how to start a community which
he linked but he it's not what I'm
looking for like I'm not looking to
start one community I'm looking to start
a meta community that we can work
through that process of what does it
take to start a community what what
would our food systems our clever
education systems look like and create
what is couple what came out of one of
the solution raisins the solution
raising on community I'll just link to
the playlist one of the it's one of the
few ideas that came out of a solution
reason that isn't technology specific
specifically it's the idea of a hundred
groups of a hundred
getting together and solving a hundred
problems for the meta community so you'd
get you know all the plumbers together
and they would solve plumbing for not
just their community but 100 communities
right like what what do we need and
plumbing and then not only like you're
not forming a community and then working
through this process you're forming a
meta community breaking off into smaller
groups to deal with to tackle the
problem right so you're not coming up
with one way to energize it as a
community because that's not going to
work for all of them have to collect the
information know what's out there decide
if and if it works and if not I don't I
don't think we're going to create our
own solar panels but evaluate what's out
there what works in what in what
communities and doing that process and
that could absolutely be done with ten
thousand people in a hundred thousand
dollars creating that platform that
looks at but it doesn't even need to be
a platform in the beginning but anyway I
hope
vision out there people respond in a way
that is how they read into the vision
just like yes I'm starting to
communities yes read this book because
it's in a way so we'll see we'll see I
put out a doodle poll of when there was
some people interested so I put out a
doodle poll that one they would like to
meet on Monday or Tuesday and hopefully
it becomes a weekly conversation but
even that scheduling people who are
global is difficult it's more easy now
the people most people were homeless for
the time but finding times that work for
people around the world but that's like
that's a problem we need to solve is
time zones that because there's people
over the world who speak different
languages are in different time zones
how do you coordinate globally I have
ideas with people okay people have to be
willing to try them I can do them and
what's the troubleshoot them figure out
what works in the desert there's also
I'm looking for people there's something
percolating in my head that's like a
Peter Joseph did it tweet about Herman
Oh somewhat starting some TV show about
solutions like no one would watch
because you're all - idiots it's
basically his personality and and then
people are like no no I watch and he's
like I'm kidding I'm not gonna actually
do that because you know podcasts aren't
I think it was a podcast of some of them
aren't as valuable is like let's say his
zeitgeist documentaries and I was like
can we just have a solutions show please
and even like Peter Joseph who I think
is brilliant and I really like the
zeitgeist movies has had a level of
success in Game a that I don't think and
because now he's so tied to the
resource-based economy and the zeitgeist
movement that he couldn't possibly see
ideas outside of that so it which is
what I've been bringing up since I
entered the zeitgeist movement like a
decade ago was you can't implement
something globally you can't dog on
everybody's religion and expect people
to come on board I have some critique of
the zeitgeist but the biggest one is
like what do we do now like how do we
actually move forward and their whole is
like well we educate people for when
there's a collapse then we'll be ready
for it I'm like that is not how the
economy sociology any of it works
hello and so
anyway but there's something percolating
about having a show of people who are
actually solving the problems like
solution raising but having it be a core
group of people who meet and develop
more of what I have in the Omega group
and hopefully becomes not just broadcast
where we're solving the problems and
everyone's jumping on board but it
inspires other people to start solution
clubs who get together and have their
own solution risings every week and then
where's a way we can compile those ideas
that come out of there and vote on them
and Co fund them together because for
people coming up with one a solution
that 10,000 people can implement with a
hundred thousand dollars doesn't work
it's basically like one person coming up
with it it we need to have a way of
developing ideas developing solutions
that are voluntary but that amalgamate a
lot of people so the risk is spread out
and people like the ideas everyone puts
in ten dollars that's not a high risk
for any of them or don't do it it's a
and so even even if and when it fails
even if it's not perfect it's not a it's
not saying it's gonna be perfect right
it's an for ten dollars you're not gonna
get an entire new food system or you
never have to pay a dollar but you might
get a food app that helps you need
healthier for cheaper and cheaper with
connection to your neighbors right so
starting point and then developing it
and making it better and better is what
we're doing we've had solution reasons
and some powerful ideas have come out of
them and then people want to move
forward with the idea and I'm like by
all means go forward with the idea but
for people creating it is just as risky
as one like you still have to get well
do you have ten thousand people no
that's the point is it like you need
first to have ten thousand people who
are willing to fund it Willie and that
the idea draws them in enough that they
can see they get more benefit than risk
and it's only ten dollars of risk so it
doesn't need to be that high of a
benefit in order to draw people in but
we're not we don't have a platform of
millions of people right so if there was
a million people who are gonna watch a
video and one tenth of one percent
signed up that would be a hundred people
they think and one hundred people
starting the community can easily elite
to ten thousand
I can get that right no one set the 1% a
thousand times a thousand is a million
so it would be a salad some people would
be was ten percent would be ten thousand
one percent would be ten thousand yes
and one in a thousand would be a
thousand well now good good job right oh
so I don't know what is happening with
oxytocin thirty six I made it's just
kind of there hoping that something
happens with it if something pops up
where it's very obvious a community
needs it or wants it I will absolutely
host one in the future but I was hoping
this one would be much more successful
and people would pair up and then we
would they want to come back another
week and then we pair them up again and
ask them to bring a friend but that's
not what happened
and it could be like I can always do
another one but I don't there's
something about asking someone to sit
with someone for an hour that we're like
not quite ready with oh we're ready for
in society but finding a way that people
can connect in a way that's powerful for
them and then bring them in and then
give them tools to generate ideas and
generate connection and small
communities that can be more resilient
it's all it is it's all coming together
it's just much more it's not something
that someone outside of our circle can
necessarily see yet it so anything
necessarily something outside of me can
see like together tech can see together
set coming together as he process
raising coming together people who are
part of solution raisings can see how
powerful that is but if you're just that
one piece of it it's not quite concrete
enough but all of it coming together and
weaving together and seeing all
everything that's coming out of game be
is amazing and I can't just look up so
that was my time stamp of when I was
gonna stop so I'll see you next time I'm
gonna do an update later on influencers
and hypocrites but first I'm gonna make
my kid breakfast